We've gathered, assessed and just cleaned our data. Are we done?
لقد جمعنا بياناتنا وقمنا بتقييمها وتنظيفها. هل انتهينا؟
No. After cleaning, we always
لا، بعد التنظيف، نقوم دائمًا
reassess and then iterate on any of the steps if we need to.
بإعادة التقييم ثم نكرر أيًا من الخطوات إذا احتجنا لذلك.
If we're happy with the quality and tightness of our data,
إذا كنا سعداء بجودة ودقة بياناتنا،
we can end our wrangling process and move on to storing our clean data,
فيمكننا إنهاء عملية wrangling والانتقال إلى تخزين بياناتنا النظيفة،
or analyzing, visualizing, or modeling it.
أو تحليلها أو تصويرها أو نمذجتها.
Sometimes we realize we need to gather more data.
ندرك أحيانًا أننا بحاجة إلى جمع المزيد من البيانات.
Sometimes we miss assessments.
وفي بعض الأحيان نفتقد التقييمات.
It's hard to catch everything on the first go,
من الصعب الحصول على كل شيء أثناء المحاولة الأولى،
and it's also very common to find
كما أنه من الشائع جدًا ظهور
new issues as you're fixing the ones you've already identified.
مشكلات جديدة أثناء إصلاح المشكلات التي حددتها بالفعل.
Sometimes our cleaning operations don't work as we intended.
وفي بعض الأحيان لا تعمل عمليات التنظيف كما أردنا.
Once we go through each step once,
بمجرد أن نمر بكل خطوة مرة واحدة،
we can revisit any step in the process any time.
يمكننا إعادة أي خطوة في العملية في أي وقت،
Even after we've finished wrangling and moved on to analysis, visualization, or modeling.
حتى بعد أن ننتهي من wrangling وننتقل إلى التحليل أو المرئيات أو النمذجة.
So don't worry if wrangling seems daunting.
لذا، لا تقلق إذا كان wrangling يبدو مروعًا.
Feel free to start small and cycle through the process a few times.
لا تتردد في بدء عملية صغيرة والبحث خلال العملية عدة مرات.